12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

I have been working professionally as a software developer, technical lead and solution architect since 2003. I am based in the Philippines. I have a wide variety of experience with different languages, frameworks and databases, primarily Java, JavaScript and Python, though I am very open to learning new technologies. I can work well in a team setting, in a leadership role, or as a solo developer. I communicate well, I learn quickly, and I always strive for excellence in my work. I am available for consulting opportunities. I prefer remote work.

Overview

2016-2020	Freelance software developer, technical lead, and solution architect consultant, various projects and clients.		
2019	BodiesApp.com - Technical Consultant		
2016-2019	Maroon Studios - Solution Architect and Technical Consultant lead		
2016-2019	Healthblocks - Solution Architect and Technical Consultant lead		
2003-2015	Azeus Systems Limited Philippines - Senior full stack developer and technical lead		
2001	University of the Philippines Diliman - Graduated BS Electronics and Communcations Engineering		
Domains	Web services, Government projects, Social care, Finance, Healthcare, Blockchain		
Specialization	Security, Performance, Accessibility, Systems Integration, API Development, Data Analytics, Reporting, Mobile (iOS and Android)		
Languages	Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, C++, HTML, CSS		
Frameworks	Django, Flask, Laravel, React-Native, jQuery, Spring, Wordpress		
Databases	SQL, Oracle, MarkLogic NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JDBC, ODBC		
OSes and Webservers	Windows, Linux, MacOS, Apache Web Server, Nginx, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Application Server, Jboss		
Services	Amazon Web Services, Google Compute Engine, Alicloud		
Standards	Accessibility (WCAG), Infosec (ISO27001), HK Gov (HK OGCIO), UK Gov (UK Data Protection Act)		

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

Career Details

2019

- BodiesApp.com Technical Consultant
- Consulting on development of a multi-tier system including mobile clients, web platform and API backends
- Working with globally distributed development and testing teams

2016 to 2019

- Maroon Studios Solution Architect and Technical Consultant
- Healthblocks Solution Architect and Technical Consultant
- Various small freelance projects

Technologies and Frameworks used:

- Node.JS + Express
- MarkLogic NoSQL
- PHP + Laravel Web Framework
- Python + Django
- Python + Flask
- Multichain
- React Native
- WordPress customisation, themes, and plugins
- Amazon Web Services (AWS) setup and deployment
- Alicloud setup and deployment
- Blockchain (Multichain and Ethereum based)

Notable Projects:

- AmberTime Coin blockchain wallet and services platform
- Ticket2Me.net online ticketing platform

2003 to 2015

Azeus Systems Limited Philippines - Technical Lead and Full Stack Developer

Project Involvement

- Major involvement in 12 projects for various departments of the Hong Kong Government, including the HK Police Force, Department of Justice, Customs and Excise Department, Social Welfare Department
- Major involvement in 3 projects for the London Borough of Camden
- Major involvement in 3 software products developed in-house
 - Coral Presenter (Powerpoint to Flash Conversion tool)

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

- Azeus Convene (Corporate meeting platform)
- AzeusCare (Social Care System targeted primarily at the UK government bodies)
- Technical consultation work in many other projects within the company
- Projects within the company are certified with Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) level 5 compliance

Roles and Responsibilities

- System Developer (from Jan 2003 onwards)
 - Coding/implementation of client-side forms-based programs, web-based systems, system reports, interfaces to third-party systems and other programs
 - System deployment and troubleshooting, diagnotics and resolution of problems in live systems
- Technical Lead (from Oct 2005 onwards)
 - Lead developer for multiple project teams ranging in size from 4-50 software developers and testers
 - Responsible for system architecture and framework design and implementation
 - Provided support for coordination work, task management and allocation for the development team
 - Conducted mentoring, code reviews and performance reviews of junior developers
 - Conducted risk management activities, including assessment of technical risks and evaluation of technical options
 - Conducted assessment and tuning of system performance problems, both during development and in live systems. This includes both application server performance and database-level (SQL) performance
 - Responsible for high-level supervision of development cycle, including ensuring efficient build and deployment processes
 - Responsible for managing security risks in the system, including making sure developers are aware of
 security-related best practices and adequate framework support is provided to minimize security-related
 problems. Includes preparation and coordination activities to ensure system compliance with 3rd-party
 security audits
 - Responsible for ensuring system compliance with various standards as required by the client systems, including but not limited to:
 - Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) for accessibility concerns
 - ISO27001 Information Security Management
 - IT Standards of the HK Office of the Government Chief Information Officer (HK OGCIO)
 - UK Data Protection Act

• Other roles

- System Analyst (from Oct 2005 onwards): Design and review of implementation of various client requirements; writing functional specifications and database design; on-site consultations with clients and technology partners to discuss requirements and iterate on implementation details. On-site locations include London (United Kingdom) and Hong Kong
- Presales Consultant (from Apr 2008 onwards): Responsible for drafting technical replies to client tender requirements for presales purposes and consulting on costing and estimation concerns
- In-House Organisation Trainer (from May 2004 onwards): Prepared organizational training materials and conducted training sessions for new hires on the following topics: SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, JSP, Java Servlets, Oracle Forms and Reports
- Skills, Programming Languages, and Tools used

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

- Web front-end languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Java, including J2EE, JSP, Java Servlets, Java Applets, Web Services
- Visual C#
- Adobe Flex and ActionScript
- Objective-C for iOS mobile applications
- Android SDK for Android mobile applications
- Python scripting
- Oracle RDBMS usage, administration and management
- Web server platforms: Apache Web Server, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Application Server, Jboss
- Third-party platforms: Liferay CMS, Alfresco CMS
- Legacy systems: Oracle Forms and Reports, Borland Delphi, Powerbuilder 6.5

Other skills (outside of work experience)

• Unity Game Development Framework

Education Attainment and Certifications

Year	Institution	
2001	College of Engineering, University of the Philippines - Diliman	Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering
2004	PhilNITS	Japan IT Standards Examination (JITSE) Certification
2012	Oracle Certified Professional	Java SE 6 Programmer